Dr. Cotter.
He's gonna die. She's gonna die.
Mom's gonna die.
I'm gonna die. Everybody dies.
I don't wanna... I'm gonna...
I haven't been able to get him to talk...
respond to me, nothing.
Just this.
Yeah. I got it.
Thanks, Dan.
She's gonna die. Mom's gonna die.
I'm gonna die. Everyone dies.
Nobody matters. She doesn't matter.
He doesn't matter. Mom doesn't matter.
I don't matter.
Nothing ever matters. I don't matter.
He's gonna die. She's gonna die.
He's gonna die. I'm gonna die.
Everyone dies.
Nobody matters. She doesn't matter.
He doesn't matter.
Everyone dies. I'm gonna die.
Nobody matters.
She doesn't matter. He doesn't matter.
Mom doesn't matter.
Nothing ever matters. I don't matter.
I'm gonna... I'm gonna...
She's gonna... She's gonna...
Everyone... I'm gonna...
I don't matter. I'm gonna... I'm gonna...
Hi, Carl.
What's going on today?
I'm dying.
No.
I don't think so.
I think you're having
another manic episode.
Don't...
Don't you tell me.
You don't know.
I feel it all around me, squeezing.
I'm scared.
Carl, I know
that what you're experiencing feels real,
but it can't hurt you.
I promise.
He's gonna die. She's gonna die.
Mom's gonna die. I'm gonna die.
Everyone dies.
Nobody matters. She doesn't matter.
Hey, Wanda.
I'm gonna put Carl Renken into observation
for a few days. He's harmless.
Just make sure someone checks on him
every couple hours.
- You got it.
- Thanks.
Hey, Dr. Desai was looking for you.
Thank you.
No! No! Please!
Please! You don't understand!
I can't go in there! No!
No! No! Please!
Come in.
Hey, did you send a patient named...
Sarah Marquet over to residency yesterday?
Yes. She has a history
with drug abuse and mania,
and she's been in and out of our unit
a few times.
Rose, she has no insurance.
Okay, but she needs treatment.
The board is down my throat
about paying out of pocket
for another bed in the residency program.
The board should try giving a shit about
the point of our job here once in a while.
I'm not questioning your judgment.
I need you to come to me first
so I can get ahead of it next time.
- All right?
- Yes.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Hey, you haven't been here
since the late shift last night, have you?
Dr. Cotter.
Laura Weaver, 26. She's a grad student.
Police were called on her
for public disturbance.
- EMS brought her in.
- Got any psych history?
Nothing on file,
but the police sent over a report
for a different incident
she was involved in last week.
And what was that one about?
A professor at her school
bludgeoned himself to death with a hammer.
She was interviewed as the only witness.
A hammer?
Hi.
Laura?
My name is Dr. Cotter. I'm a therapist.
Do you wanna sit down?
Okay.
I know you're nervous.
That's okay.
I just wanna have a chat.
I promise this is a safe place.
Not for me.
Why do you say that?
Come on. Let's sit.
Please.
Okay. I'm gonna ask you some questions
that might sound stupid.
What day of the week is it?
Thursday.
And the month?
October. I'm not crazy.
- Nobody's saying that.
- No, but I need you to understand.
I'm a PhD candidate.
I'm not some lunatic. Okay?
Let's just take a breath,
and you can just tell me what's going on.
I'm seeing something.
Something no one else can see
except for me.
I know how insane that sounds. I do.
But it's... This thing, I can't explain it.
What is it you're seeing?
It looks like people,
but it's not a person.
I'm not sure I understand.
It looks like people.
It looks like different people.
Sometimes it pretends to be someone
that I know.
Sometimes it's a random stranger.
Sometimes...
Sometimes it looks like my grandfather
who died in front of me when I was seven.
But it's all the same thing. It...
It's... It's like...
It's like it wears people's faces
like masks.
Okay. Do you see it right now, here?
What happens when you do see it?
It's smiling at me.
But not a friendly smile.
It's the worst smile I've ever seen
in my life.
Whenever I see it,
I just get this god-awful feeling
like something really terrible
is gonna happen.
I've never felt scared like I do
when I see it.
Laura, have you
or anyone else in your family
ever experienced hallucinations?
It's not a hallucination, no. It's real.
You don't get it. It does things to me.
It causes shit to happen around me.
It's taken over my whole life
and my mind and...
it tells me things.
It told me that today... Today's the...
Today's the day that I'm... I'm gonna...
Okay. That's okay.
That's okay.
I know that what you're experiencing
feels incredibly real.
Sometimes,
when we get emotionally overwhelmed,
or experience an intense trauma,
our minds want to...
You're not listening to me.
My God.
I'm gonna fucking die,
and no one will listen to me.
Okay. Laura, it's okay.
God.
Hey, it's okay. Laura.
Hey, can you look at me, please?
It's okay.
Look at me.
My God. No!
No! It's here!
- Get away!
- Laura. It's okay.
- It's just us.
- Please! No!
- There's nobody else here.
- No!
No!
My God.
I have a patient emergency in eval 2.
I need staff here now.
Hurry.
Laura?
Had Ms. Weaver
ever been a patient here before?
No.
Would you say she was typical
of the patients you see here?
This is an emergency psychiatric unit.
Typical is not really a thing here.
Right. But she was a head case, yeah?
I'm sorry, a head case?
I think we're just trying to get
your opinion of her mental state.
She could've been suffering from...
acute post-trauma psychosis.
She was having paranoid delusions.
What kind of delusions?
She was convinced that some...
sort of evil presence was haunting her.
Yikes.
It's just, we're gonna have to contact
Ms. Weaver's family
and attempt to explain what happened.
So we're looking for anything
that might make some sense of all this.
If there's anything else you can tell us,
that... that might help.
Before she died...
she was... smiling.
Yeah, she sounds fucking crazy to me.
Rose.
Whoa.
My bad. Did I scare you?
I didn't hear you come in. Shit.
- Hi.
Hi.
What's up?
Nothing. Sorry.
Something's wrong.
A patient died today.
My patient.
Hey, come here.
I'm sorry.
It happened right in front of me.
It was awful.
I'm so sorry. What can I do?
This is a nice start.
Maybe we should bail on dinner tonight.
We can't.
Holly hired a sitter,
and she's gonna be a bigger headache
if we don't go.
No way. Holly turning into a headache?
Hey.
I'm sorry, you want to talk to me
about being tired?
Now that Jackson's in the first grade,
I'm literally up at 6:00 a.m. every day
to make him breakfast and pack him lunch.
God knows what kind of nonorganic garbage
that cafeteria is even serving.
Then I have to drive him to school,
barely have any time
to run my own errands.
I haven't been to Pilates in weeks.
- Okay, my body is so fucked.
- Not true.
Then I have to go back to school,
pick him up,
then I have to take him
to either soccer practice,
swim lessons, karate, theater...
And he just started taking Spanish.
I mean, my weekdays
are literally impossible.
You are coming Saturday, right?
What?
Sorry, what's Saturday?
- I'm sorry, is that a joke?
- Wow.
Rose, Jackson's seventh birthday party.
I've told you, like, five times.
I can't. I have work.
- What do you mean work? It's Saturday.
- I work Saturday.
See, this is exactly why you have to
get out of that gross hospital
- and into a private practice...
- Gross?
- It is not gross.
- to work normal-people hours.
Rose, there have to be
plenty of crazies out there
who will actually pay you for your time.
Thank you so much for your input, Greg.
That's very sweet.
I'm just saying, why become a doctor
if you can't get disgustingly rich?
You're kidding, right?
Rose loves being a doctor.
She'd do it for free.
Well, on the subject
of wasted earning potentials,
- we could sell the fucking house.
- Can we not right now?
I don't understand.
It's just sitting there.
We grew up in that house.
Rose, it's a total teardown.
Why not just get the money for the land?
Can you guys just shut the fuck up?
Wow.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I've been looking forward to this.
You okay?
Yeah.
Morning, Doc.
Morning.
Hey. Yesterday,
that patient, Laura Weaver...
The police had sent a report
about a different incident
that she was involved in.
- Can you get that forwarded to me?
- You got it, Doc.
Also, I was supposed to have
a session with Jane Park.
Yeah. She pulled out
a bunch of her hair overnight
and swallowed it all.
They took her down to medicine
to have her stomach pumped.
Shit.
Rose.
- What... What are you...
- I was on a call nearby,
and I just thought I would...
We didn't really get to talk yesterday,
other than the whole... whole thing.
And I just wanted you to know that,
when the call came in,
I had no idea it was gonna be you.
So, I'm sorry if that was weird.
It's your job. I get it.
How you been?
Joel, why are you here?
Like I said,
I was on a call nearby, and I just...
I thought I would...
come check on you.
After everything that happened yesterday,
that's not an easy thing.
Okay. I appreciate it,
but I don't need you to check on me.
Right.
No, yeah, I mean... Sorry.
I have to get back to work.
- Yeah.
- See you around.
You do know she's engaged, right?
Yeah.
I'm single.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Look, I just wanted to say sorry
about last night.
I shouldn't have
kept going at you like that.
No, I...
I should apologize.
I've been just dealing with some stuff.
I wasn't being very good company.
Okay. if you can't make it
to your nephew's party tomorrow,
you could at least get him a present.
If you need an idea,
he's really into electric model trains.
You sound weird. Are you okay?
Yeah, no, I'm fine.
Hey, Carl.
How are you feeling today?
Carl.
Carl?
She's gonna die. I'm gonna die.
- Everybody dies.
- Carl, look at me.
You're going to die.
You're going to die. You're going to die.
- You're going to die.
- Help!
Help! This patient is 5150!
- He needs to be restrained!
- Go, go, go!
No! No!
No!
No! No! No! No!
No! No!
No!
He was aggressive.
Acting psychotic.
Carl Renken has been
in and out of here a dozen times
and has never exhibited behavior
even remotely aggressive.
- Do you think I'm making it up?
- Of course not.
But yesterday, a patient in your care
killed herself brutally in front of you.
Is it possible, when you presumed
that Carl Renken was a danger to himself,
that that's what your mind
was reacting to?
I suppose I could've misinterpreted
the situation and overreacted.
Okay.
So, here's what's gonna happen.
You're gonna take a paid week off.
Morgan, that's really not necessary.
You've been working 80-hour weeks
for months.
I'm concerned
that you haven't been sleeping.
We can't help these patients unless
we have our own mental health in check.
And it's in the unit's best interest
if you just take a week
and clear your head.
Just do what you gotta do
and come back focused, okay?
Fuck!
- Hello?
- This is First Line Security.
May I have your name and the passcode?
Rose Cotter.
"Acapulco."
Ma'am, we've detected a door alarm.
Yeah, the... the back door
of my house is open.
Are you alone in the house, ma'am?
Yes.
Are you sure?
What?
Are you sure
you haven't let something inside, Rose?
Look behind you.
Shit.
Hello?
This is First Line Security.
May I have your name and the passcode?
We did a full sweep inside and out.
It's all clear.
What about the back door?
Is it possible it wasn't fully latched
last time it was closed?
I don't know. Maybe.
I wouldn't worry about it.
These false alarms happen all the time.
If anything else comes up,
you can give us a call.
Okay.
Evening, sir.
Evening.
What happened?
Mustache?
Mustache.
So, is there a reason you set the alarm?
I literally don't remember doing it.
I must have just, like,
set it by accident or something.
By accident?
Sorry. Sorry.
My head has just been in this, like,
foggy, creepy, spacey place all day.
And there was this weird incident at work,
and then...
And then my boss is making me take a...
Sorry.
- Everything's okay.
- Are you sure?
No, I'm fine. I was just venting.
Okay.
Can you see if you can find Mustache?
I haven't seen him anywhere at all.
Yeah.
Rose, did you break another glass?
Mustache?
Come on, kitty.
Please. Please.
Mustache.
It looks like people.
It looks like different people.
Sometimes it pretends to be someone
that I know.
Sometimes it's a random stranger.
Sometimes..
Sometimes it looks like my grandfather
who died in front of me when I was seven.
But it's all the same thing. It..
It's smiling at me,
but not a friendly smile.
It's the worst smile I've ever seen
in my life.
Whenever I see it,
I just get this god. awful feeling
like something really terrible
is gonna happen.
My God! No! No!
No! It's here! Please!
Get away! Please! No!
I have a patient emergency in eval 2.
I need staff here now. Hurry.
Laura?
Rose.
Rose!
Rose?
Whoa! My God! Rose! Rose! Whoa, whoa!
What the fuck? Rose, put the knife down!
Rose!
Hi.
Rose?
This is a surprise.
It wasn't so much the blood.
It was...
her face.
The look that she had.
How did it make you feel?
Terrified, obviously.
Vulnerable.
Guilty.
Guilty?
Well, she was my patient.
She was a disturbed young woman
you only met for ten minutes.
Yeah. I just...
I feel like I've gotten stuck on it.
I can't, you know, get it out of my head.
Have you considered
the reason you feel stuck
could actually be more about
your mother's suicide?
Do you still blame yourself?
That...
I'm really not trying to relitigate
that part of my life right now. So...
What would you like to talk about?
I was hoping that I could get
a script for Risperdal.
Ever since that...
patient, I've been...
seeing things...
and hearing things.
I'm sure it's just a symptom
of post-trauma.
Let's avoid any self-diagnosis.
What is it you've been seeing and hearing?
Echoes of what happened with my patient.
You know, just fleeting moments
of stress-induced hallucinations.
But when they're happening, they feel so...
corporeal and unsettling.
Rose, from where I'm sitting, you don't
seem delusional or disordered to me.
And certainly not psychotic.
It's my impression
this experience with your patient
triggered old anxieties compounded
with too much stress, not enough sleep.
You have wounds
that have never fully healed.
It's possible they never will completely.
That's the nature of trauma.
But you can learn to get control over it.
Have you been continuing to see patients
while you've been coping with all this?
- No. I'm just taking a short hiatus.
- Good.
If you want my advice,
use this time to do something different.
Anything that will take your mind off
the triggers that are causing you stress.
I also think it would be helpful...
if we resumed our regular sessions again.
Sure.
And what about the Risperdal?
Just... You know.
Let's talk again next week
before we consider any medication.
In the meantime, you can always call me.
Sure.
No, I asked you
for a white wine spritzer. Jesus.
- My God. You made it.
- Hi. Surprise.
Come on in. Come on in.
I thought you had to work?
- I decided to take the afternoon...
- I'll take that.
Hey. Greg. What are you doing?
I told you not to take those out yet.
Geez.
Ladies, I have to go corral
my dipshit husband.
Would one of you please show my sister
to the adult refreshments?
Sure. We have a stash
in the kitchen. Come on.
Wait. You're that therapist, right?
Yes, I am.
Fantastic. Can I ask for advice?
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday...
So cool.
Gracias, Harper. Gracias, Harper's mom.
That one's from Aunt Rose.
Open it!
Rip it open!
What'd you get, sweetheart?
No. No...
- My God.
- No, no. Mustache.
- What the hell is wrong with you?
- This can't be happening.
No. No, no.
No, I promise you, this wasn't me.
It wasn't. It wasn't me, I swear.
You have to...
You guys have to believe me, please.
Somebody please fucking believe me.
What the fuck are you?
Leave me the fuck alone!
You see her. You have to see her.
Please, Holly,
tell me that you see somebody.
Please.
- Hey, Rose.
- Fuck.
I heard you were brought into the ER.
I wanted to come check on you.
How're you doing?
Fine.
It was just an accident. Thank you.
Yeah. They said that you had
had an anxiety attack.
Rose, I'll be honest with you,
I'm concerned.
And I mean this as your friend,
but I really think
you should speak to someone.
Are you seeing anybody professionally
right now?
Rose, are you listening?
Wait.
I need to tell you something,
and I need you to know
that I'm not crazy, okay?
- Okay.
Something is happening to me.
And it's gonna be really hard
for you to believe.
Maybe we should just go inside.
No, wait. Just listen to me!
Sorry. Sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Okay...
Something is threatening me.
Some kind of evil spirit, or energy.
I don't really know what it is, but...
But I think that it killed my patient.
Because she described experiencing
the same thing before she died.
And now it's somehow
attached itself to me.
And...
I'm just really scared
that something bad is going to happen.
I really need you to say something.
What do you want me to say?
I want you to believe me.
Rose, you're talking about
a fucking ghost.
No, no, no. It's not...
It's not a ghost.
It's something else.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I can't.
I cannot fucking do this right now.
No. Trevor.
Whoa, wait. No, no, no. Don't walk away.
I need you...
You're not listening to what I am saying.
Okay, Rose. What the fuck am I supposed
to say to respond to this right now?
Do you hear yourself?
Jesus Christ. You sound crazy.
I am not crazy!
Sorry. Sorry.
But it's genetic, isn't it?
What?
Mental illness.
You can inherit it from a parent.
I looked it up.
Why would you look that up?
Because...
I wanted to know what I was
potentially hitching my entire life to.
Is that so fucking unfair?
I'm going in the house.
No, no, no. Please, Trevor. I'm in danger!
Rose.
- Did you kill Mustache?
- No!
No! That was not... That was not me.
Then tell me, what happened to him?
It was the... thing.
Trevor, please.
Please. Please.
Rose.
Come here.
Baby...
Please. Help me.
- Mommy made a mistake.
- No, no, no.
No, no, no.
Rose!
- Look where you're going! Are you crazy?
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
Mrs. Muñoz?
At first, I noticed small changes in him.
Then it all happened so fast.
He was on edge.
Paranoid.
He would wake up
in the middle of the night, screaming.
I'd never heard him scream before.
Then he just stopped sleeping altogether.
I would catch him
having these conversations with himself.
He was seeing things.
Doing strange things
that he didn't even seem to remember.
Then one morning he was gone.
That night, the police called
and told me he was dead.
They asked me to identify his body.
His face.
Twenty. five years of marriage,
and that's what I have left
to remember him.
I'm so sorry.
Did Gabriel ever
describe the things that he was seeing?
I'll show you.
I should take it all down,
but I can't stand being in here.
This is what Gabriel said he saw.
He kept saying
it was trying to get inside of him.
That is Gabriel's brother.
He died in an accident.
Twenty years ago.
Gabriel never got over it.
How long had this been going on?
Ever since he got back
from that damn conference
he would go to every year.
It was because he saw
that awful woman kill herself.
But no one reports on that.
He watched someone die by suicide?
Yes.
- I assumed you knew this.
- What was her name?
I don't remember. I'd have to find it.
Did... Did he ever...
say why all of this was happening?
Did he find any explanation
in all of this?
What kind of reporter are you?
Mrs. Muñoz, your husband was not insane.
The things that he was seeing,
they're real. I've seen them.
- What are you, a fucking nutcase?
- What?
Some kind of morbid fanatic?
How fucking dare you?
No, please. Please.
What happened to your husband
is happening to me.
Out of my house.
I want you out of my house, now.
Just please give me the name.
Just give me the name!
Get the fuck out of my house!
Fuck. Shit.
Yeah?
Hey.
Come on in.
Finally got rid of that ugly yellow couch.
So, what's up?
I assume you're not here to catch up
considering the cold shoulder
the other day.
I need a favor.
I need you to
not ask any questions about it.
Terrific. Yeah, let's hear that.
So, nine days ago,
a man named Gabriel Muñoz killed himself.
I need to know if he had been involved in
any other recent police reports.
Can you find that out? Here. For me.
Come on. Are you serious?
This is my one day off. Go to the station.
Joel, please?
Fine.
Goddamn it.
All right, what was his name again?
Gabriel Muñoz.
All right. I see the report on his death.
Yeah. There's another incident report here
from a week earlier,
from a precinct upstate.
What was it for?
He gave a witness statement.
He was staying at a hotel
where a woman committed suicide.
Okay. And what was her name? The woman?
Angela Powell.
She's a real estate agent.
What is this?
- Fuck.
- What? What is it?
It's a picture from the scene.
- Let me see it.
- No.
- No, no.
You don't wanna see this.
This is, like, evidence.
Or, just, you know, have at it.
Holy shit.
Told you it was gross.
Okay.
I need you to do the same search again,
but this time on her.
The woman, Angela.
Can you please tell me
what this is all about?
Joel, you said you weren't gonna
ask me any questions.
No. You said I wouldn't ask you
any questions...
Joel, I need your help.
Okay?
Please?
There was a previous report
filed four days before her death.
That's a weird coincidence.
She was also interviewed about a suicide.
What is this? Is that a video file?
It's security camera footage.
- Put it... Put it on.
- Just... It's loading.
What the fuck is this?
You know, my day was going just fine.
- Can you rewind it?
- Really?
Rewind it, Joel.
Okay, stop.
Is he smiling?
Rose, who are these people?
I have to go.
Where are you going?
Rose, where are you going?
What is going on here?
- I'm so confused right now.
- Can you do me one more favor?
Do you have a printer?
Trevor. Trevor, you here?
Hey.
Hi, Rose.
What is this? What is she doing here?
I wanted to see how you were doing.
I was talking to my fiancé.
I called her.
Why?
Because you've been acting
completely unhinged.
- I don't...
- And I... I didn't know what else to do.
Are you fucking kidding me?
I came to you. The person
I'm supposed to trust most in the world,
and I confided that I was scared to death.
That I needed you.
And you didn't listen
to a word I was saying.
No. Why do you think I even called her?
- All I'm trying to do here is help you.
- No!
All you're trying to do is make it
so you don't have to deal with it.
You're fine as long as everything
is easy and agreeable,
but God forbid anything become real,
or even a tiny bit difficult.
And... And you just...
You think about how it's gonna fuck up
your whole little perfect life plan.
- Whoa. Are you serious right now?
- Yeah.
If that's how you feel,
then why are we even together?
- Maybe I just don't know.
- Why don't we all take a breath...
Why don't you just
fucking make yourself at home!
Rose, are you actually leaving right now?
- Greg.
- Rose, what are you doing here?
- Is Holly here? I need to talk to her.
- I don't think that's a good idea.
Let me talk to my fucking sister,
okay? Holly!
You're gonna come
and talk to me like that?
Holly, can I talk to you,
just for one sec?
- No, I don't think...
- Can I please talk to you?
I don't think this is a good idea.
Honestly.
- It's fine. It's fine.
- Holly.
- Just go the fuck inside.
- I don't think... All right. Fine.
Jesus.
Okay, okay, okay.
How are you?
My eyes are open now.
I have been cursed.
Or somehow wrapped up in a curse.
I got it from my patient.
She was cursed, and then when she died,
she transferred it to me.
And now I'm being threatened by this...
this entity.
- By an entity?
- No, no. It's what killed Mustache.
It was at the party yesterday,
but you couldn't see it.
Nobody else can see it, except for me.
Jesus Christ.
No. Look, Holly.
I know it's so hard to believe,
and it was difficult for me
to believe it at first either.
But look... look at this. Look.
My God. Rose.
Why the fuck do you have that?
Because this has happened to other people.
- And they're all dead.
- Rose.
And... Holly, I'm gonna be next!
Rose, curses are not real.
Okay? You are having some sort of a...
a breakdown.
What? No, no. Holly.
You're not hearing me.
- You are not hearing me.
- Rose.
This is exactly what happened to Mom.
You sound just like her.
How the fuck would you know that?
- I'm sorry, what?
- You were never around when Mom got bad.
Where the fuck were you when she died?
You have no idea
what you're talking about.
Okay? Because I was older,
I got the worst of Mom's insanity.
I had to fucking leave the house.
That was the only way I could survive.
And I'm... I'm sorry...
that I left you alone and that
you had to be the one to find her.
I know that that fucked you up, and...
And I know that that's not fair.
And I wish I could do something about it.
But, Rose, I have tried so hard
to move on with my life,
to leave all of that shit behind me, okay?
But you, it's like
you can't accept the fact
that Mom lost her mind
and fucking killed herself.
And you let it define your entire life,
and you punish me because I don't want to.
I'm sorry that I'm actually trying
to help people
instead of being some fucking
stay-at-home PTA housewife,
who lives in her own
self-centered, smug little bubble!
- Okay.
- I don't know why I said that.
You know what, I'm not doing this.
I'm not doing this with you.
You've completely traumatized Jackson,
okay?
I can't have you around
when you're like this.
Fuck.
Holly?
Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
Joel?
Why didn't you tell me about
your patient's connection to the others?
- Wha...
- After you left, I kept digging.
These cases? This same pattern.
It goes back further.
So far, I've found 20 cases
involving 19 suicide victims
with a direct line
linking them all together.
And the things these people are doing
to themselves, Rose. Holy shit.
Wait, you said 20 cases,
but only 19 suicides.
One of the cases mixes up the pattern.
Some accountant, Robert Talley.
His business partner commits suicide
right in front of him,
and four days later, Talley goes
and fucking murders a woman
he's never met,
completely out of the blue.
But get this, a week later,
the key eyewitness to the murder
also commits suicide.
Pattern resumes.
- So, he's alive?
- Yeah.
He's sitting in holding in Altoona.
Joel, I gotta talk to him.
- I'm gonna need you to say something.
- Yeah, I... I will.
Just... Just...
Give me a second. I mean, Jesus...
I thought you were gonna say
this was some kind of, like,
crazy suicide cult, or blackmail scheme.
- I mean, this? This is... This?
- But, Joel.
Okay.
Let's just put aside the possibility
that some sort of evil,
extraordinary force could even exist.
What you're saying
is that this thing is jumping around
from person to person,
and it is causing them to kill themselves?
Okay, but maybe it's not suicide.
What do you mean?
Okay. So, my patient, she was terrified,
but she was not suicidal.
And then at the end,
everything about her changed.
It was like the person
I had been talking to was gone.
And something else had taken over.
So, it's... it's kind of like the guy.
- On the security camera footage?
- Yes. Yes. Exactly like that.
My God. What the fuck?
In the cases that you found...
how long was it
between each victim's death?
None of them survived longer than a week.
Some of them didn't even make it
past four days.
Today was my fourth day.
Hey.
Whatever happened to those people,
it's not gonna happen to you.
I promise.
Transfer guard to gate three.
- Thank you.
- Give them a buzz through. They're clear.
I owe you one for this, Doug.
You're just lucky that he fired
every lawyer he was assigned.
You do know what this guy did, right?
Well, Dr. Cotter's building
a psychological profile
on a similar case for us.
Well, Talley's a whole box of fruit loops.
So, good luck.
Look, you only got
ten minutes with him, okay?
It's the best I could do
without a court order.
Well, I appreciate it.
Mr. Talley, my name is Dr. Rose Cotter,
and I was hoping you'd be willing
to answer some questions about...
I'm done answering questions. I confessed.
I actually don't care about
what you were accused of.
What I need to know
is what you experienced
in the days leading up to it.
I have a patient...
a young woman.
Four days ago, a man killed himself
right in front of her.
And ever since then,
she has been seeing something.
Something that pretends
to be other people.
The man that she saw kill himself,
he claimed that he was seeing
the exact same thing.
What the fuck do you want from me?
- What is it?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
Why is it that everybody else
who's seen it is dead and you're alive?
Why? Please.
Mr. Talley, you can help her. Okay?
Please.
Make the cop leave.
Not gonna happen, pal.
Make him leave,
and I'll tell you what I know.
Joel, please.
I'll be outside, all right?
I tried to research anything
and everything I could about this thing.
There's been other chains in the past.
Found one that was in Brazil
a few years ago.
A man there escaped that chain...
by killing his neighbor
and passing it to his neighbor's wife.
Your patient is going to die
unless she kills someone.
That's the only way you can get rid of it.
The only way.
She has to make sure there's a witness
for it to pass to,
'cause this thing needs trauma to spread.
That's what gives it power. Trauma.
Your patient has to make it count.
Tell her to use some kind of weapon.
Make the biggest mess she can...
I can't kill someone!
You?
You have it?
No, no, no.
Why the fuck did you come here?
You're not giving it back to me.
- Get out of here! Get out of here!
- I'm sorry.
Get her away from me!
Hey.
Hey! Wait.
- What happened in there?
- Nothing.
What'd he say?
Nothing.
Nothing?
He's out of his fucking mind, Joel.
Fuck.
What are you doing here?
I apologize
if you felt ambushed yesterday.
- That was the wrong approach. I'm sorry.
- Yeah.
- I think you should go.
- Rose,
we both know I have a responsibility
to notify the authorities
if you're a danger to yourself or others.
I need you to help convince me
you're not a danger.
Trevor mentioned there had been
talk of ghosts.
I never used the word "ghosts."
Evil beings, then. Paranormal.
I admitted to him
that I was seeing things,
the same thing that I told you.
That's not happening anymore. Okay?
It was stress and lack of sleep.
I confided in him,
and that was obviously a mistake.
But that's it.
Okay? Are we good?
How are you feeling today?
Let me think...
I'm pretty sure my fiancé
thinks I'm crazy.
My sister has just... totally shut me out.
And now...
my former therapist
is making unannounced house calls
to ensure that I am not a danger.
So, other than that, I'm really good.
Should you get that?
What?
Rose, it's Madeline.
I've been trying your mobile all morning.
I'm very concerned about
how we left things yesterday.
- Rose? Are you there?
- No.
Hello?
- Rose?
No. No.
Almost time, Rose.
What the fuck are you?
Please.
No, no.
No. No, no.
No.
Hey, Dr. Cotter.
Aren't you supposed to be on leave?
Just grabbing something from my office.
Carl. Hi.
- No. No.
- It's okay.
No, no, no.
- God.
- Just calm down.
- No! No, no!
Shut the fuck up.
Just calm down, okay? Okay.
Rose.
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
Rose, you can't be around patients.
Fuck! Rose!
Fuck!
Rose, what are you doing here?
Nothing.
I don't... I don't know.
I don't know why. I...
Why don't we go inside
and we can just talk?
No! It's...
It's not safe.
Rose, I don't think you should
be alone right now.
I need to be alone.
I need to be... I need to be alone.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I have to go.
Rose, I don't think you should
go anywhere, okay?
You just relax, I'm gonna make
a phone call, all right?
Rose. Rose, don't go anywhere.
Wait. Rose, please.
Please don't go anywhere, okay?
Just hang...
Rose. Rose, wait! Rose!
Joel.
I just saw a police APB go out for you
that says you're dangerous.
What the fuck happened?
- I know what I need to do.
- What?
This thing, it needs all of its victims
to pass it on in order to survive,
but if there's no one else around,
then it has no way to pass.
As long as I'm alone,
I can deprive it of what it needs.
That doesn't make any sense.
Your plan is to just avoid people forever?
I am not gonna keep running, okay?
I've got to face it.
Okay, Rose, I'm coming to you.
Just tell me where..
Rose.
Baby...
Help me, please.
Mommy made a mistake.
Get the phone.
Call for help.
Rose!
Rose.
It's okay, baby.
Come here.
I am so sorry.
I... I haven't been a good mom.
I want to be. I really try to be,
but sometimes everything is just too much.
There is something terrible inside of me.
- I hate myself.
- Stop. Stop. Stop.
Are you ashamed of me?
No.
Then why did you let me die?
- Why didn't you save me?
- It's not my fault.
- You could have called for help.
- Stop. Stop it.
- But you didn't.
- Stop it.
- You wished that I would die.
- Because I was afraid of you!
I was ten years old...
and you were a monster.
And I know that it's not fair. You...
You needed help.
But I couldn't.
And I have carried that guilt...
for my entire life.
And I... I have to let it go.
I have to let it go.
This is not real.
But Rose,
your mind makes it real.
What are you?
Why are you doing this to me?
Because your mind...
is so inviting.
You can't escape your mind, Rose.
It's...
It's my mind.
You can't escape it either.
Rose!
Holy shit.
Are you okay?
- Can I just come in for a sec?
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Where have you been?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for dragging you into
my whole fucked-up mess.
For most of my life,
I've been afraid of
letting people get too close,
because I was afraid of...
what they might see if they really looked.
And so I... I put walls up,
and I kept people at a distance.
And then...
I met you,
and I could feel those walls coming down.
And it scared the shit out of me.
And so...
I was selfish,
and that was not fair to you.
And I am so, so sorry.
And I'm...
I'm being selfish again by even asking,
but do you think that...
That I could stay here and just...
just sleep?
Could you...
stay with me while I sleep?
Please.
Yeah, of course I'll stay with you.
I'll stay with you forever.
No.
No, no, no, no.
No, no.
No.
Rose.
No, no, no!
Rose!
Rose, open the door!
Open the door.
Rose!
Rose.
No!
- No!
- Fuck.
Hold on. I'm coming!
No!
Rose!
Rose.
Rose?